The black forceps' secret is still being protected.
看來還沒有人知道黑色止血鉗的秘密
Indeed.
是啊
But I must ask you to be cautious.
不過，你還是要謹慎行事
Please dispose of this as usual.
這個還是跟以前一樣，幫我處理掉
I understand.
知道了
And the old administrative documents,
還有舊的行政文件
shall I move them to the storage room here?
是不是要搬來這裡的保管室呢？
Yes.
對
That's fine.
可以
Then I'll start on that soon.
那我馬上去辦
Excuse me.
先失陪了
Is this everything?
這些全都要嗎？
Yes. Please bring it to the hospital storage room.
對，都搬去醫院的保管室
Thanks again.
辛苦你們了
-Right. -Okay.
-是 -好的
We can't do this in a day.
這些一天搬不完吧
You're right.
的確是
Excuse me.
不好意思
If you're looking for the hospital, it's that way.
您要去住醫院本部的話，在那邊
Thank you very much.
謝謝你
But that's okay.
但沒關係
I know this hospital quite well.
這家醫院我很熟
They're taking care of my son.
我兒子在這裡受到照顧
So you're here to visit him?
那您是來探望兒子的嗎？
No, not like that.
不是
He's a doctor.
他在這裡當醫生
His name is Seishiro Tokai.
他叫渡海征司郎
Dr. Tokai?
渡海醫生？
You're Dr. Tokai's mother?
您是渡海醫生的母親嗎？
-It's a pleasure to meet you. -Likewise.
-幸會 -您客氣了
I thought I would pay a visit to Dr. Saeki,
我原本打算去拜訪佐伯醫生
but my son never answers his phone.
但我兒子一直不接電話
Is that so?
這樣啊
That boy…
那孩子…
He couldn't give a damn if I were alive or dead.
從來都不管我的死活
Completely apathetic.
有夠冷漠的
-That can't be. -I mean it.
-怎麼會呢？ -我說真的
How about we all get some lunch?
那不如我們一起去吃午飯吧？
Ms. Kinoshita.
木下小姐
Dr. Tokai is in an emergency operation.
渡海醫生好像在動緊急手術
-Dr. Sera. Artificial valve. -Right.
-世良，人工血管 -是
-4-0.
-4-0縫線
-I'm supposed to be the operating surgeon. -Here it is.
-明明我才是執刀醫生 -來了
-Felt. -Oh, please.
-組織修補片 -麻煩你了
-Felt, hurry. -Right, sorry.
-修補片，快點 -是．抱歉
-You should have it cut. -Okay.
-應該提早剪好的 -是
Here.
這裡
-Suction. -Sorry.
-抽吸 -抱歉
The other day, Dr. Tokai made me a delicious egg-on-rice bowl.
前幾天渡海醫生請我吃了 美味的生蛋拌飯
-He did? -Wow.
-真的嗎？ -對
I would love to try that.
我也好想嚐嚐看
Would either one of you be so kind
那要不你們誰
as to marry my son?
跟我兒子結婚吧？
What?
什麼？
You'll be able to eat delicious rice for the rest of your life.
下半輩子都能吃到美味的米飯哦
My husband was a lover of food,
先夫說世上有各式各樣的食物
but he loved rice the most.
但他最愛的還是米飯
He would always make rice balls to bring to operations.
動手術時，也總是做成飯糰帶過去
-Operations? -That's right.
-動手術？ -對
He was a surgeon at Tojo University.
他曾是東城大學醫院的外科醫生
He was a surgeon? Wow!
原來是這樣！
My husband would always say,
他生前總說
"The most ordinary people make the best doctors."
“只有普通人才能成為好醫生”
-Ordinary people make good doctors. -Right.
-普通人才能當好醫生 -對
I have a photograph.
我這裡有照片
-Would you like to see it? -Yes.
-想看嗎？ -好啊
Certainly.
一定要
Dr. Saeki is in it too.
還有佐伯醫生呢
Really?
真的嗎？
Ms. Harue?
春江女士？
Ms. Harue, are you okay?
春江女士，您還好嗎？
There's a large tumor inside her heart.
心臟裡長了一顆巨大的黏液瘤
She likely fainted when it incarcerated.
應該是腫瘤造成阻塞，才導致她昏倒
We have to tell Dr. Tokai.
那渡海醫生那邊…
He's in another operation. Not now.
渡海醫生正在進行別的手術 告訴他現在不行
-We need to do an emergency surgery. -Right.
-總之先動緊急手術 -是
-Spoon. -Here.
-手術匙 -這裡
-Left atrial myxoma excision complete. -Okay.
-左心房黏液瘤摘除完畢 -是
We'll move on to suturing the left atrium. 4-0.
接下來進行左心室縫合，4-0縫線
MOM 4 MISSED CALLS
（老媽，四通未接來電）
Pardon me.
打擾了
Dr. Tokai.
渡海醫生
It's your mother…
是您母親…
You're here. It was a sudden incident.
你來了，之前情況很緊急
Dr. Kurosaki operated on her.
是黑崎醫生幫忙動了手術
Her condition is stable.
現在情況穩定了
Thank you.
謝謝
Let's be thankful that she's all right.
很慶幸她穩定下來了
Can I ask you to leave?
能請您出去嗎？
I see. Very well.
那好吧
Take care.
保重
-Doctor. I prepared the test. -Thank you.
-教授，已經做好試驗的準備了 -謝謝
Tell Dr. Kurosaki that he'll be in charge.
轉告黑崎讓他來負責
Right.
是
What are the odds of Dr. Tokai's family being admitted?
渡海先生的家人來住院也太湊巧了
I'm sure he's worried as well.
想必他也很擔心
I'm not talking about that Dr. Tokai.
我說的不是這個渡海醫生
I'm talking about Dr. Ichiro Tokai.
而是渡海一郎醫生
You are a disgrace!
真是東城大學之恥！
Do you understand what you've done?
你知道自己做了什麼嗎？
What would we have done without Dr. Saeki?
要是沒有佐伯，這事要怎麼辦？
How will you take responsibility for this?
你打算怎麼負責？
Harue coming here at a time like this.
春江女士在這個時間點來到這裡
It's a thing of the past.
都是陳年往事了
However, make sure it's not investigated.
但別讓外界太關注這件事
-Be careful. -Understood.
-小心行事 -知道了
I can't believe Dr. Tokai's mother is here.
真沒想到送來的會是渡海醫生的母親
We'll do the post-op exam tomorrow.
明天要進行術後檢查
Tomorrow?
明天嗎？
By the way, it sounds like it will finally be here tomorrow.
話說明天那樣東西 終於要來我們醫院了
Oh, that?
大家是這樣傳
The thing on everyone's mind.
大家心心念念的那樣東西
MEDICAL SUPPLIES ON BOARD
（醫療用精密機器運輸車）
Japan's first operating robot developed by Daiichi Industries.
就是第一重工正在研發的 日本第一部手術機器人
The domestically produced Darwin, also known as Caesar.
國產的達爾文機器人，又稱為凱撒
Its first clinical trial in Japan will be done at Tojo,
日本的首次臨床試驗 將要在東城大學醫院舉行
and it will be handled by the esteemed Dr. Saeki.
而且由地位崇高的佐伯教授您負責
What an honor.
真是太榮幸了
Why did Tojo become the trial facility for the new Darwin?
東城大學之所以成為 國產達爾文機器人的臨床試驗場所
Thanks to Dr. Nishizaki,
是因為西崎教授
and the involvement of the Ministry of Health.
以及厚生勞動省的想法
Excuse me.
失陪
You're Dr. Saeki, right?
您是佐伯醫生吧？
-Yes. And you must be from the ministry… -I'm Tomizawa.
-您是厚勞省的… -我是富澤
It's an honor to meet you, Dr. Saeki.
很榮幸見到您本人
-Hello Dr. Saeki. -Ms. Kinoshita, you're here too?
-您好，佐伯醫生 -木下小姐，你也來了？
We were invited by Dr. Nishizaki.
我們是應西崎教授之邀
That's right, Dr. Saeki.
正是如此，佐伯醫生
Mr. Tomizawa was kind enough
實際上，富澤先生
to read the recently published Snipe article.
已經看過近日發表的醫狙器械論文
Oh, that one…
是嗎？醫狙的論文…
Your name was included as a research partner, correct?
您也在論文裡掛名為研究夥伴吧？
Yes, well…
對，這個嘛…
The future of medicine relies not only on individual skill
未來的醫學界不光靠個人的技術
but also on the integration of the latest medical technologies.
還要結合最先進的醫療科技
Wow. Did you hear that?
您聽到了嗎？
Truly a fantastic philosophy.
多麼了不起的理念
There is, in fact, a new device that can make your philosophy a reality.
實際上，有一個最新的醫療器械 可以實現您的理念
Dr. Nishizaki is leading the development process
由西崎教授主導研發的
of a domestically produced Darwin.
國產達爾文機器人
Mr. Tomizawa has asked for your help.
富澤先生請您提供協助
He's suggesting that we ask for your cooperation
他建議我們商請您合作
in the development process.
偕同研發
Research from Teika University.
負責研究的帝華大學醫院
Practical skill from Tojo University.
和負責實際操作的東城大學醫院
If both universities join forces,
倘若這兩所大學能夠聯手
we can surpass the foreign-made products that rule the industry.
勢必能超越 目前雄霸業界的外國製器械
I believe we can complete our own Darwin with this method.
藉由這種方式 我有信心我們能做出國產達爾文
They got me.
我被擺了一道
All Dr. Nishizaki is looking for
說到底，西崎教授想要的
is Impact Factor.
無非是影響因子
Impact Factor is gained from being published in academic journals.
透過在學術雜誌上刊登論文 得到的影響因子
Currently, Dr. Saeki is leading the race.
目前仍是佐伯教授更勝一籌
But if the domestically produced Darwin is completed,
但是，如果國產達爾文成功研發
the Impact Factor will be given
後續帶來的影響因子
to the project leader, Dr. Nishizaki.
都將歸該項目的領導人西崎教授所有
There was no benefit for Dr. Saeki.
佐伯教授分不到任何好處
It would appear the new Darwin
看樣子這個國產達爾文機器人
has only just passed animal trials.
才剛通過動物實驗階段
With the Ministry of Health involved, we can't simply ignore it.
既然厚勞省插手了 我們也不能坐視不理
And you plan to oversee it, don't you?
你也是其中一個監督角色嗎？
If a Japanese Darwin is developed,
如果國產達爾文研發成功
it will be great progress for Japanese medicine.
日本的醫療將會大幅躍進
I hope that…
我希望…
I can lend a hand in that.
自己也能盡一分力
Thus, despite various unclear motives the Japan-made Darwin, Caesar,
就這樣，在各種動機影響下 國產達爾文機器人凱撒
arrived at Tojo University as an unwelcome guest.
不受歡迎地來到東城大學醫院
"Caesar" is the hero who laid the foundations
“凱撒”是為古羅馬帝國
of the ancient Roman Empire.
奠定基礎的英雄
Caesar is a Latin name.
凱薩是拉丁名字
This Caesar will be the foundation to change the future of the medical field.
希望它也能成為 改變未來醫療界的基石
That's how it got its name.
所以才取這個名字
Wow. It's beautiful!
真是太漂亮了
It's a bit smaller than the foreign model.
比外國生產的款式還小
And only one arm instead of four.
而且機械臂不是四根，只有一根
With this one arm,
光靠這一根機械手臂
multiple tasks such as migrating and suturing can be performed.
就能完成血管結紮和縫合等多項工作
Incorporating the most advanced technology in Japan,
這是結合了日本最尖端技術的
it is the ultimate medical robot.
終極醫療機器人
We'll leave the Caesar to Dr. Takashina.
讓高階去負責凱撒
Are you sure?
這樣沒問題嗎？
He seems to have cut ties with Teika,
雖然他和帝華大學醫院已經斷絕關係
and there was the Snipe incident.
但是畢竟醫狙出過事
We need someone to take responsibility if something happens.
萬一出了什麼問題 還是需要他去背黑鍋
Right. I see.
是，我知道了
How is Harue Tokai's condition?
渡海春江女士的情況怎麼樣？
She's currently being examined.
她正在接受檢查
I see.
我知道了
However…
不過…
Dr. Tokai.
渡海醫生
Here.
這個
In Harue Tokai's exams,
渡海春江的術後檢查
something awful was discovered.
發現了嚴重的問題
An overlooked tumor in the pulmonary vein of the left atrium?
沒注意到左心室肺靜脈上的腫瘤嗎？
That's right.
沒錯
Overlooking the pulmonary vein is not an entirely uncommon error.
不過，看漏肺靜脈這種事 並不是太罕見
For a novice surgeon.
新手外科醫生才會這樣
Let's have a conference and form a plan.
總之先開會討論，商量對策
Get it started at once.
馬上去辦
Understood.
知道了
Of all people…
為什麼…
Why did it have to be Dr. Tokai's mother?
偏偏會是渡海醫生的母親？
About Harue Tokai.
關於渡海春江女士
In her exams,
檢查結果顯示
we discovered a tumor in the pulmonary vein of the left atrium.
心臟肺靜脈裡還有腫瘤殘存
Dr. Kurosaki.
黑崎醫生
Why was the tumor overlooked?
為什麼會有腫瘤殘存？
We removed the myxoma in the surgery yesterday.
昨天的手術摘除了黏液瘤
However, it was extremely difficult to see the pulmonary vein
但是肺靜脈的深處很難看清楚
and part of the tumor was left unremoved.
所以有一部份黏液瘤沒有清除乾淨
So you mean it was human error?
所以是你疏忽了？
So the one who put the patient in danger was…
那麼，讓患者面臨這麼大危險…
Dr. Kurosaki.
黑崎醫生
Who's responsible for this?
這到底是誰的責任呢？
Drop it, Tokai.
渡海，適可而止
I understand how you feel,
我理解你的心情
but a pulmonary vein oversight is not unreasonable.
但是看漏肺靜脈 某種程度上也是沒辦法的事
We cannot cast the blame on the surgeon.
不能把責任全推到執刀醫生身上
I see. Understood.
這樣啊，明白了
Dr. Tokai is actually backing off.
渡海醫生還真的屈服了
Nothing would get done if we did everything by his rules.
全按照渡海醫生的標準來看 根本什麼事都做不了
I'll place responsibility
那這次的責任
on the hospital.
就算在院方頭上吧
What? On the hospital!?
什麼？院方？
Director Moriya.
守屋院長
As a family member of the patient,
我以病患家屬的身分
I demand a settlement of 20 million yen.
要求院方支付我 2000萬日圓作為和解費
-Twenty million? -It's only fair.
-2000萬？ -很合理啊
This is medical malpractice.
這明顯是醫療過失
Just as Dr. Saeki said, this kind of thing
可是佐伯教授也說了，這種情況
is not uncommon.
並非完全不可能
I haven't made a single error in my entire career.
我可是從來都沒有犯過任何失誤
Then let me operate on her.
那就由我替她動手術吧
I decline.
我拒絕
-What? -That's hospital logic, isn't it?
-什麼？ -因為那是院方的說辭
Completely incomprehensible from the patient's perspective.
站在患者的立場，我完全無法理解
You're not planning on operating on her yourself, are you?
你該不會是想要親自執刀吧？
Twice in Tojo's past,
東城大學過去曾經發生過兩次
doctors have failed while operating on family members.
醫生替近親執刀 最後手術失敗的案例
Since then, we have banned doctors from operating on people close to them.
從那之後 就禁止醫生為家屬進行手術了
This is Tojo University's rule.
這是本院的規定
Of course I know that.
我當然知道
Then what do you plan on doing?
那你到底要怎麼樣？
Until this is settled,
在同意和解之前
we put the operation on hold.
手術先暫緩
-Twenty million for a medical error? -Yes.
-以醫療失誤為由索賠2000萬 -對
However you put it, he's asking too much.
無論如何說，這要求都太不合理了
It is his mother, after all…
畢竟是他自己的媽媽…
I think it's more about the money.
但也有可能就是單純為了錢
He even turned down Dr. Saeki's offer to operate.
他甚至拒絕由佐伯教授動手術
-He did? -Yes.
-是喔？ -對
I heard that Dr. Tokai's father used to be an operating surgeon at Tojo too.
我聽說渡海醫生的父親 以前也是東城大學的外科醫生
-Seriously? -Yes.
-真的嗎？ -對
His mother told me.
是他母親說的
She even had a photograph of him with Dr. Saeki.
她有一張他們夫婦和佐伯教授的合照
I've had the feeling that Dr. Tokai and Dr. Saeki
我總覺得佐伯教授和渡海醫生
have some sort of special relationship.
有種很特別的關係
Yeah.
是啊
I wonder what happened.
不知道發生過什麼事
I didn't think Dr. Tokai would react like that.
渡海那傢伙居然有那種反應
Forgive me. It's all my fault.
非常抱歉，都是我的錯
Don't sweat it.
別在意了
When the patient wakes up, we'll get consent for a second operation.
等患者清醒後 再去取得再次動手術的同意
-I'll take care of the negotiations. -Thank you.
-到時候我親自去交涉 -謝謝
But still…
不過
I never thought I would hear Dr. Tokai say the words "medical malpractice."
真沒想到渡海會說出 “醫療過失”這個詞
Absolutely. Is he trying to get back at us
就是說啊，明明是他父親做出那種事
for what his father did?
現在是要來報復嗎？
Dr. Tokai. Good afternoon.
渡海醫生，你好
I heard about your mother.
我聽說了令堂的事
I don't know what to say…
我不知道該說些什麼…
It's none of your business.
和你無關
I also heard that you
我也聽說你
refused Dr. Saeki's operation.
拒絕由佐伯教授動手術
It is true that medical malpractice cannot be overlooked.
確實，醫療過失不能視而不見
Asking for a settlement is only fair.
要求和解金也很理所當然
However…
但是…
Is that really the only reason you refused?
你真的只是因為那些原因 拒絕手術嗎？
It's none of your business.
不關你的事
It's you.
是你啊
Where am I?
這是哪裡？
You're at Tojo University Hospital.
您在東城大學醫院的病房
We were having lunch and I…
我本來跟你們在吃飯…
I'm glad you've woken up.
您能清醒太好了
Dr. Saeki seemed quite worried.
佐伯教授也很擔心的樣子
Dr. Saeki? He did?
佐伯教授？
After what my husband did…
我丈夫給他添了麻煩
Now, I'm the one causing him trouble too.
現在連我也要給他添麻煩了
Yes?
你好
Have you decided on a test patient for the Japanese Darwin?
你決定好用哪個患者 做國產達爾文的臨床實驗了嗎？
We have a candidate, but no negotiations have been made.
已經確定合適人選，但還沒進行交涉
I see. Make sure you are well-prepared.
這樣啊，一定要準備就緒
Understood. Everything is going well.
明白，一切都沒問題
But because this will be the first human trial,
不過，這是第一次對人體 進行臨床治療
I think it's best to be extra cautious.
我認為必須格外謹慎
Cautious? What are you talking about?
謹慎？什麼意思？
So what if it's a human trial?
人體試驗又怎麼樣？
It's just another test subject. No different than an animal.
只是研究對象，跟動物沒有一樣
Got it, Dr. Takashina?
懂了嗎，高階？
I asked you to infiltrate Dr. Saeki's inner circle
我是為了搞定國產的達爾文
in order to secure the Japan-made Darwin.
才要你滲透佐伯教授的信任圈
If you don't get me results,
如果還是不能交出結果
I'll mean it next time.
這次我會硬起來
You'll have nowhere to return to.
你休想再回到這裡
Begin the testing at once.
盡快進行試驗吧
Understood.
明白
I need nurses in the emergency room!
急診室需要護士！
-Hurry! -Okay!
-快點 -是
Hurry up! Go!
快點，快過去
There was an accident at a nearby construction site!
附近的工地發生坍塌事故
-Twenty-seven victims are on their way. -Twenty-seven?
-有27名傷患正要送過來 -27個？
Everyone on your feet! Let's go.
全員出動，快點！
Okay!
是
Dr. Tokai. We need you.
渡海醫生，我們需要你
Got it, Dr. Takashina?
你明白嗎，高階？
I've asked you to infiltrate Dr. Saeki's inner circle
我是為了搞定國產的達爾文
in order to secure the Japan-made Darwin.
才要你滲透佐伯教授的信任圈
Begin the testing at once.
盡快進行試驗吧
Dr. Takashina.
高階醫生
I'm glad to see you looking well.
您清醒過來太好了
I'm Dr. Takashina, a cardiac surgeon.
我是心臟外科的高階醫生
Nice to meet you.
幸會
I'm feeling much better.
我感覺好多了
I would actually like to have a word with you about that.
我有點事想跟您商量
-I'll be leaving then. -No.
-那我先告辭了 -不
I would like you to stay here.
請你也留下吧
All right then.
好的
I'm going to speak to you frankly.
我就開門見山說了
While we performed emergency surgery on your heart,
雖然您的心臟動過緊急手術
there appears to be a tumor left in your pulmonary vein.
但是肺靜脈上仍然有腫瘤殘存
We'll have to perform a second operation as soon as possible.
必須盡快再動一次手術
But you don't need to worry.
不過請放心
We have the perfect solution for this case.
對這種情況 我們有最合適的解決方法
With the approval of Dr. Saeki,
現在佐伯教授正在大力推廣
we'll operate using brand-new technology recently introduced to Tojo.
用東城大學引進的 最新醫療器材進行手術
-Dr. Saeki approves? -Yes.
-佐伯醫生推廣的？ -對
Are you familiar with Darwin surgery?
您聽說過達爾文手術嗎？
You guys, over there!
你們過去那邊！
We need antibacterial! Now!
拿消毒水過來！
Antibacterial! Bring antibacterial!
誰能拿消毒水過來，消毒水！
-This is not good. He needs surgery. -Okay.
-狀況很糟糕，快送去手術室 -是
-We'll do it here. -Here?
-不用了，就在這裡做 -在這裡？
-Nekota.
-在這裡嗎？ -貓田
Bring me an incision set and electroscalpel.
把開胸套具和電動手術刀拿過來
Okay.
是
Get me some scissors, hurry.
把剪刀拿過來，快點
This trial in particular is of great significance.
而且這場手術具有重大意義
The affordable and compact Japan-made Darwin, named Caesar.
價格實惠又小巧的 國產達爾文機器人凱薩
If we can fully implement it,
如果能讓它投入實際運用
small, local hospitals like this one will be able to use it as well.
未來就連地方的小醫院也能使用
In some cases where a skilled surgeon is present,
當然，像令郎那樣
much like your talented son,
醫術這麼優秀的外科醫生
the machine won't need to be used.
有可能不需要依賴醫療器械
But unfortunately, I am just an ordinary doctor.
但是很遺憾，我是普通人
And unfortunately, that's the case for most doctors.
大多數醫生也都跟我一樣是普通人
My husband would always say,
他生前總說
"The most ordinary people make the best doctors."
“只有普通人才能成為好醫生”
We need the Caesar.
我們需要凱薩
There are countless patients like yourself that we need to help.
往後用來治療像您一樣的病人
For their future as well,
為了實現那個未來
can I ask for your cooperation?
您願意協助我們嗎？
I understand.
我知道了
I'm happy to help in any way I can.
我願意盡我所能幫忙
Thank you.
謝謝您
In that case,
那麼
may I ask for your signature, please?
請您在這裡簽名
OPERATION CONSENT FORM
（手術同意書）
Over here, please.
麻煩了
Dr. Tokai, what about this one?
渡海醫生，這位患者怎麼辦？
Don't you kill a single one of them.
一個也不許死
Move!
快行動
-Almost done. -Okay.
-就快好了 -是
-Metz. -Here.
-手術剪 -這裡
Pulmonary vein suture complete.
肺靜脈縫合完成
-That was fast. -Sew up the left atrium.
-好快 -你來縫合左心耳
Okay.
是
Wait. You can't ask an intern to do that.
請等一下，不能交給實習醫生去做吧
I see…
是嗎？
-Please. -Here.
-麻煩了 -這裡
He'll do it.
他會完成
He has the skill. Don't worry.
他有能力，別擔心
Hey, can you do sutures on the left auricle?
你能做左心耳縫合嗎？
Interns are not allowed to do that yet.
實習醫生還不能做
Sera is always having a hard time with Dr. Tokai.
世良老是被渡海醫生刁難
But it would seem our boy here doesn't realize how much he's improved.
但他好像還沒有意識到 自己成長了多少
-No time to waste! Move it! -Okay.
-別浪費時間了，快動起來！ -是
Finish the connection for me.
幫我做連接吧
Right.
是
You finish up.
你來完成
He's incredible.
真是厲害
Doing all this by himself.
全都一個人包辦
Oh, Seishiro.
征司郎
What's that?
那是什麼？
Meeting again after all this time and that's the first thing you say?
這麼久沒見面 第一句話就是這個嗎？
Caesar trial documents.
是凱撒的臨床試驗資料
Trial?
試驗？
The consent forms have already been signed and submitted.
凱薩手術的同意書已經簽名提交了
A nice doctor visited me just now
剛才有一個人挺好的醫生過來
and explained it thoroughly.
詳細地跟我做了說明
I've decided to trust him.
我就決定交託給他了
Why are you writing that?
為什麼要簽那種東西？
Listen.
聽我說
The doctor told me.
醫生說過了
If the device can be made popular,
如果那個機器普及了
they'll be able to save countless more patients.
能救治更多患者的性命
He is such a caring doctor.
他真是志向遠大的醫生
Not like you, always so narrow-minded and cold.
不像你，總是偏執又冷漠
Always thinking about yourself.
永遠只想到自己
Causing trouble around here, I'm sure.
應該給大家添了不少麻煩吧
What did you do?
你幹了什麼？
The Caesar
這具凱薩
was specifically designed by the Japanese for the Japanese.
是專為日本人量身定做的醫療器械
You could say it was made specifically for your mother.
甚至可以說是為春江女士量身定做的
Don't get it twisted.
別弄錯了
I explained everything about the treatment in detail
我跟她詳細說明了治療過程
and got her approval.
也得到她的同意
This is what she wants to do.
她想要這麼做
It's what you want.
是你想要吧
I always put the patient's wishes and needs first.
我向來把患者的想法擺在第一位
And tomorrow,
明天
-we will hold the trial operation. -Impossible.
-我們要進行試驗手術 -不可能
Until I've got a settlement,
在和解金的事情談妥之前
I said the operation is on hold.
我說了手術要暫緩
It's always about the money, isn't it?
說到底還是為了錢嗎？
What?
什麼？
Participating in this medical trial is your mother's best option.
參與這次的醫療試驗 是令堂的最佳選擇
I may not be as skilled as you,
我雖然沒有你的高超醫術
but I have the Caesar.
但我有凱薩
I will save lives with technology.
我要利用科技來救人
I don't trust that technology.
我不相信科技
Putting her life in the hands of some cheap machine.
居然把生命託付給這種破爛器械
What a foolish patient.
患者真是太蠢了
I promise to show you that the Caesar can succeed.
我一定會用凱撒成功完成手術
For your mother, and myself.
為了春江女士，也為了我自己
And if it fails…
那麼如果失敗了
you can both die.
你就一起去死吧
The patient agreed to Darwin surgery?
患者同意用達爾文做手術嗎？
Forgive me.
抱歉
While I was occupied, Dr. Takashina…
在我忙碌的時候，高階醫生他…
It doesn't matter.
沒關係
If the patient has agreed, all that's left is to hope for success.
既然患者同意了 我們只能祈禱手術成功
Are you sure it's okay?
這樣真的沒問題嗎？
This will support the Caesar's development--
這麼做會有助於凱撒的研發…
And it will erase your error as well.
你的失誤也能被抹除
Isn't that just ideal?
這樣不是很好嗎？
That's true, but…
這倒是，但…
Listen.
聽著
In my hospital,
在我的部門
there is no room for error in surgery.
不允許有手術失誤
Even the slightest error.
哪怕是微小的失誤也不行
Understood.
是
Dr. Tokai agreed to use the Caesar?
渡海醫生同意用凱撒了嗎？
Yeah.
對
Using a robot for his mother's surgery…
讓自己的媽媽用機器人動手術
I can't believe he agreed.
渡海醫生居然會同意
Yeah…
是啊
But because it's family, he won't be allowed in the operating room.
但他是家屬，沒法參加手術
That's right.
沒錯
So even if something bad happens,
那如果發生什麼意外
we can't count on Dr. Tokai to save the day, can we?
渡海醫生也沒法補救了嗎？
Right. If he even touches a scalpel, he'll be fired.
是的，只要碰到手術刀 他就會被開除
Fired?
開除？
It looks like you're prepared.
看來你準備就緒了
With the Caesar, we'll only need to make incisions in two places.
使用凱撒，只需要在身體上開兩個孔
There will be no burden on the patient.
不會增加患者的負擔
With a precision camera installed on the arm,
機械手臂的前端裝有高解析度的鏡頭
we'll be able to perform a high-level operation with full internal visual.
可以直接看著體內的患部 進行最高階的手術
-Dr. Takashina. -Harue Tokai is asking for you.
高階醫生，渡海春江女士找您
I'm so sorry to disturb you.
抱歉打擾了
No problem. Dr. Tokai is always…
別這麼說，渡海醫生他
helping me out.
經常關照我
-He is? -Yes.
-是嗎？ -是的
That boy?
你說那孩子嗎？
You can't be serious…
不可能吧
-I mean it. -Ouch.
-是真的 -好痛
-Are you all right? -Yes.
-沒事吧？ -沒事
So…
那麼…
-What can I do for you? -Right…
-您有什麼事嗎？ -對
I would like to talk about tomorrow's operation.
關於明天的手術 ，有點話想跟你說
It's nothing much.
不是什麼大事
Just one thing.
只是有一點
I'm always nagging you to eat more and get enough sleep.
我常常跟你說要好好睡覺、好好吃飯
Be a helpful person. That's all you need to do.
當個有用的人，這樣就夠了
People survive by helping each other.
人與人之間要互相扶持才能活著
There's only so much you can do on your own.
靠自己的能力有限
It hurts…
好痛…
Mom?
媽？
The residual tumor is causing disturbances in her blood flow.
應該是殘存腫瘤阻礙了血流
Then we'll be able to operate with the Caesar as planned.
這樣可能要按計畫用凱撒動手術
But the patient's blood is Rh-minus.
但患者的血液是RH陰性
Because of the accident earlier, we don't have enough transfusion.
由於白天的事故，血庫庫存不足
There's only 600cc remaining.
只剩下600cc了
Only 600cc?
剩600cc？
The Caesar doesn't need an incision. It can be done.
凱撒不需要開胸，夠用了
If something goes wrong, we won't have enough blood.
但只要出一點差錯，這些量就不夠了
I will complete the operation without trouble.
我會順利完成手術的
The fateful day arrived sooner than planned.
就這樣，決定性的日子 比預定提早到來
Preparations complete.
準備就緒
We will now use the Japan-made Darwin, Caesar,
那麼現在開始 用國產達爾文機器人凱撒
to remove a residual tumor in the pulmonary vein.
摘除肺靜脈的殘存黏液瘤
-Let's begin. -Yes, sir.
-拜託了
The arm is now entering the body.
機械臂插入
Japan's own Darwin at its first operation. Who knew it would happen so soon?
日本第一台達爾文手術 居然能這麼早進行
I'm thankful we got the patient's consent.
多虧得到病患的同意
I've called him in as a family member of the patient.
因為他是病患家屬，所以才請他過來
-Remove the blood. -Okay
-清除血液 -是
It's earlier than scheduled…
比預定的時間早啊
-The first robotic surgery. -Let's hope it works out.
-第一場機器人手術 -希望順利進行
-Opening the left atrium. -Right.
-切開左心室 -是
It can work so precisely. Amazing.
好厲害，居然能做到那麼精準
It works even faster than the foreign model.
速度也比國外生產的快
Amazing! It's beating all expectations.
好厲害，性能超乎想像
The Caesar is able to operate with only two small incisions.
凱撒的優點是 只需要在身體上開兩個孔
The final challenge is the tumor stuck to the pulmonary vein.
最後的挑戰是摘除 黏在肺靜脈上的腫瘤
Will they be able to remove it?
真的有辦法摘除嗎？
They can't miss by 0.1 millimeter.
連差0.1公厘都不允許
Don't worry, it's a robot. They don't make mistakes.
別擔心，那是機器人，不會有失誤
We'll now remove the tumor.
現在開始摘除黏液瘤
It's all going according to plan.
很好，目前一切都按計畫進行
Removal complete.
摘除完成
Debakey.
組織鑷
Okay.
是
Tumor removal complete.
黏液瘤摘除完成
-4-0. -Right.
-4-0縫線 -是
Left atrium closed.
左心室關閉完成
We did it.
成功了
Flow down. Declamp.
降低輸液流量，解除阻斷
Well done!
做得好！
It's small, but we have bleeding.
有少量出血
-What? -Please stay calm.
-怎麼回事？ -保持冷靜
The Caesar is ready to perform recovery.
用凱薩進行修復
-Bring transfusion. -Right.
-輸血 -好的
They have to transfuse blood quickly.
他們必須盡快輸血
But because of the accident this afternoon,
但因為下午的事故
there's hardly any transfusion left.
儲備血液差不多用完了
What's happening?
怎麼回事？
It would appear to be a hemorrhage in the aorta.
看起來主動脈裡面一直在出血
The Caesar's camera gives a limited view.
凱撒的鏡頭拍攝範圍有限
They must have damaged the tissue while finishing the operation.
一定是在進行主動脈阻斷時 傷到裡面的組織
This is the last of the transfusion.
這是最後一包血了
-Blood pressure, 82! -The bleeding won't stop!
-血壓82 -還是出血不止
-What should we do? -We stop the bleeding with Caesar.
-怎麼辦？ -用凱撒來止血吧
-Dr. Kurosaki. Your support, please. -Got it.
-黑崎醫生，請您協助一下 -好的
Not enough blood?
血液不足？
The patient's blood type is not common. She has Rh-minus.
病人的血型是非常罕見的RH陰性血
Do what you can to collect more blood.
想辦法調配血液過來
We need Rh-minus!
我們需要RH陰性血
Contact all local hospitals and facilities.
立刻聯繫附近的醫院和機構
-Understood!
-是
-How much do we have left? -200cc.
-還剩多少血可以用？ -200cc
That's all?
只有這麼一點嗎？
Toyoake Hospital has some!
豐明醫院有血！
It will be here in one hour.
一小時後可以送來
One hour… that's too late.
一個小時…太慢了
-We're looking for Type A Rh-minus. -Excuse me.
-請問有人是A型RH陰性嗎？ -打擾一下
Does anyone here have Type A Rh-minus blood type?
有沒有哪位的血型是A型RH陰性？
Type A Rh-minus. Is there anyone who can cooperate?
A型RH陰性血 請問有誰可以幫忙？
Damn it! Finding Rh-minus is not easy.
可惡， RH陰性血哪有那麼容易找
It'll take more time.
要花很多時間
-We don't have enough time. -Blood pressure dropping more!
-要來不及了 -血壓一直在降低
This is bullshit.
可惡
Isn't there anything you can do?
沒有辦法了嗎？
If this operation doesn't succeed,
如果手術失敗了
development of the Caesar will be halted completely.
凱撒的研發就會立即中斷
That's none of my business.
這不關我的事
I've also been prohibited by the patient's family from operating.
而且患者家屬一直都拒絕由我來執刀
But…
但是…
At this rate, the patient will lose her life.
這樣下去，患者將會性命不保
The only person besides me who can save her, is Dr. Tokai himself.
除我之外，就只有渡海能救她了
You didn't want me to do it, so you refused.
你拒絕由我來執刀
If that's the case…
這樣的話
You'll have to do it yourself.
只能由你自己去做了
However,
但是
due to Tojo's rules,
按照東城大學的規定
you'll have to face punishment.
你將會受到處分
If that doesn't bother you,
如果你不在乎的話
then go.
你就去吧
-We got the transfusion. -That's all?
-血來了 -只有這些嗎？
Sorry, this is all we have so far. Here you go.
抱歉，現在就只有這些，麻煩了
-Where is the bleeding coming from? -We don't know.
-出血位置在哪裡？ -還不知道
-Blood pressure, 72. -She's running out of blood.
-血壓72 -她的血快流光了
We can't retain blood volume!
輸血跟不上失血量
-Dr. Tokai… -What are you doing here?
-渡海醫生 -你怎麼會來這裡？
You don't have permission to operate.
你還沒有被允許做手術
-Let it go. I'll take responsibility. -Professor?
-沒關係，之後我會讓他負責 -教授？
Dr. Tokai…
渡海醫生
Move this.
把這個搬走
You're in my way.
很礙事
Get out of the way.
搬走
-I'll open up. -Okay.
-我要下刀了 -是
A median sternotomy now?
現在開始從正中開胸嗎？
-Scalpel. -Here.
-手術刀 -是
Impossible. Even if you find the wound, there is not enough blood.
不可能，就算找到出血位置 供血量也不足
If it's blood you need, I have it.
如果需要血，我有
I'm Type A Rh-minus.
我是A型RH陰性血
I have no infections. I can help.
也沒有傳染病，我可以幫忙
Get me blood donation packs.
請幫我準備捐血工具包
-Hurry! -Right.
-快點 -是
We cannot let this operation fail.
絕對不能讓手術失敗
Use as much as you need.
要多少盡管抽
Help me out.
過來幫忙啊
Okay.
是
-Twister. -Here.
-鎖緊器 -這裡
-4-0. -Right.
-4-0縫線 -是
-Two pieces of felt. -Okay.
-兩塊修補片
Found it. I'll suture now.
找到了，開始縫合
-Cover me. -Right.
-跟上 -是
-More suction. -Okay.
-繼續抽吸
-Suction. Deeper. -Right.
-抽吸，往更裡面去 -是
-Move the PA. -On it.
-避開肺動脈 -知道了
-Don't pull too hard. -Right.
-不要太用力拉扯 -是
-Deeper. -Okay.
-再進去一點
Dr. Takashina! That's enough…
高階醫生，不能再抽了…
Keep going.
繼續
It's no good. Dr. Takashina's blood is not enough.
不行，光靠高階醫生的血不夠
-Go deeper with the suction. -Right.
-抽吸器再進去一點 -是
-More to the side. -Understood.
-再避開一點 -知道了
We have transfusion! Bacteria-free and fully inspected.
血來了，感染和適應性都檢測過了
-This is all of it! -Bring it here!
-全都沒問題 -快拿過來
Right.
是
-Here. -Thanks.
-這裡 -謝謝
They made it…
終於趕上了
-Prepare the Metz. -Okay.
-準備手術剪 -是
-Metz -Here.
-手術剪 -這裡
Suture complete.
縫合完成
What's her condition?
患者情況如何？
Blood pressure…
血壓…
stabilizing.
穩定了
They saved her…
終於獲救了
Recovering from a condition like that…
這種情況下還能力挽狂瀾…
Dr. Tokai really is something.
渡海醫生真了不起
Dr. Tokai knew about Dr. Takashina's blood type all along?
渡海醫生早就知道 高階醫生的血型了嗎？
-You finish up. -Okay.
-你來收尾 -是
Dr. Tokai…
渡海醫生
I'm very sorry.
真的非常抱歉
You had planned from the beginning
從一開始你就打算
to operate on your mother, right?
替你母親動手術吧？
You're surprisingly hard to kill off.
你的命還真硬啊
Dr. Tokai has broken Tojo University's rules.
渡海打破了東城大學的規定
We cannot simply ignore this.
絕對不能坐視不管
-You're right. -Please wait.
-沒錯 -請等等
Before that…
在此之前…
Would you take a look at this, please?
請你看一下這個
Dr. Tokai, it's about your mother's condition.
渡海醫生，關於令堂的情況
Post-op exams show no problems.
術後檢查一切正常
-I see. -Yes.
-是嗎？ -對
Also…
還有…
Look at this.
看看這個
It's your mother's consent form.
這是令堂簽署的手術同意書
OPERATION CONSENT FORM
（手術同意書）
You can see here
你看這裡有一個
that a request was added to the note.
附加條款
"If my condition worsens and my life is in danger,
“如果我的情況惡化，性命垂危
I would like to request
希望最後
that my son, Dr. Tokai, finish the operation."
由我兒子渡海征司郎來執刀”
The patient's wishes are the first priority.
患者的要求是第一位
This means that your actions
所以您的行為
will have no consequences.
沒有任何問題
What an incredible woman,
真是了不起的女性
your mother.
您的母親
Good morning.
早安
Could you help me up?
可以幫我把床搖起來嗎？
Sure.
是
Where is he?
那孩子呢？
Dr. Tokai is currently in another surgery.
渡海醫生正在動另一個手術
I see.
這樣啊
So…
那麼
he wasn't fired after all.
他沒被開除吧
How did you know…
您怎麼會知道…
I'm sorry.
很抱歉
I heard it.
我都聽到了
So even if something bad happens,
那如果發生什麼意外
we can't count on Dr. Tokai to save the day, right?
渡海醫生也沒法補救了嗎？
Right. If he even touches a scalpel, he'll be fired.
是的，只要碰到手術刀 他就會被開除
Fired?
開除？
I know the trouble he has caused all of you.
雖然那孩子給大家添了不少麻煩
But I couldn't allow him to get fired.
但也不能隨便開除他
He still has work to do.
至少要讓他保有工作
He still has patients to save here.
在這裡救助更多病患
He has to make it up to you all.
這樣才能彌補你們大家
I don't mind if I come in second place.
我不介意自己退居第二位
That boy, to me,
對於我來說，那孩子
is everything.
是最重要的
You don't have to worry about me.
不必擔心我沒關係
Dr. Sera?
世良醫生？
-Are you crying? -I…
-你在哭嗎？ -我…
-I'm sorry. -Hey.
-不好意思 -嘿
When you see Dr. Saeki,
如果你看到佐伯醫生
please give him my regards.
請替我問候他
I will.
我會的
So you're saying the Caesar still has issues?
也就是說凱撒還是有一些問題嗎？
That's right.
對
However,
不過
analysis and countermeasures
已經做完分析，也已經採取
have already been taken.
相應措施了
You don't need to worry.
您不必擔心
You've finished the analysis? Well done, Dr. Nishizaki.
已經分析完了？做得好，西崎教授
Tojo University operates,
東城大學負責手術
and Teika University analyzes.
帝華大學進行分析
HARUE TOKAI
（渡海春江）
As for the election,
在理事長選舉之前
I expect to present a good paper by then.
應該可以交出不錯的論文
CARDIAC SURGERY PAPERS
（心臟血管科論文）
"Seigo Saeki…"
佐伯清剛…
"Ichiro… Tokai"?
渡海一郎…
Dr. Tokai.
渡海醫生
Tell me just one thing.
請告訴我一件事
Why were you against Dr. Saeki operating on your mother?
你為什麼反對由佐伯教授執刀？
Because I don't trust that man.
因為我不信任他這個人
That man…
那個人
betrayed my father.
背叛了我的父親
A person's greatest enemy is other people.
人最大的敵人是自己
No matter where I go, my job remains the same.
無論我到哪裡，工作還是不變
It seems this patient's case is perfect for the clinical trial.
看起來這個病患很適合做臨床試驗
How did they get our patient's information?
他們怎麼會有我們病患的資訊？
I even wished she would die.
我巴不得她死掉
You've betrayed the patient!
你背叛了病患
What is Teika researching, a cover-up?
帝華大學在研究什麼？是幌子嗎？
Hurry up and save the patient.
快點救病人
He's the devil of the operating room.
他是手術室的惡魔
You're still running away after all this?
你努力走到這一步 就是為了再次逃避嗎？
Tell me. Who was it?
告訴我，到底是誰？
Subtitle translation by: Tom Grathwol
字幕翻譯：莊雅婷